<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<Defs>
	<!-- PatchNoteTypes: Undefined, Hotfix, Patch, Minor, Major -->
	<FactionColonies.PatchNoteDef Name="EmpirePatchBase" Abstract="True">
		<modId>saakra.empire</modId>
		
		<links>
			<li>https://discord.gg/f3zFQqA</li>
			<li>https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2571437524</li>
			<li>https://rimworld-empire-mod.fandom.com/wiki/Rimworld-_Empire_Mod_Wiki</li>
		</links>

		<linkButtonImagePaths>
			<li>GUI/Buttons/discordlogo</li>
			<li>GUI/Buttons/nguilogo</li>
			<li>GUI/Buttons/wikilogo</li>
		</linkButtonImagePaths>

		<linkButtonToolTips>
			<li>Join the Empire discord!</li>
			<li>The layout of this GUI was made using NesGUI, a tool for modders that helps with creating RimWorld GUI! Click to learn more.</li>
			<li>Check out the Empire Wiki! (Some of the contents will be outdated)</li>
		</linkButtonToolTips>
	
		<authorStringBase>All of the code for this update has been developed by {0}.</authorStringBase>
		<introStringBase>A new update for {0} has been released: v.{1}. The following changes have occurred:</introStringBase>
	</FactionColonies.PatchNoteDef>
	
	<FactionColonies.PatchNoteDef ParentName="EmpirePatchBase">
		<defName>0_39_00</defName>
		<label>Patch note update</label>
		<description>In this update, we introduce to you our new patch note window!</description>
		
		<major>0</major>
		<minor>39</minor>
		<patch>0</patch>

		<releaseDay>6</releaseDay>
		<releaseMonth>12</releaseMonth>
		<releaseYear>2021</releaseYear>
		
		<patchNoteType>Minor</patchNoteType>

		<patchNoteLines>
			<li>- added the option to force open some float menus as suggested by LunaW0lve on our Discord server. (Check the third image for more details!)</li>
			<li>- added translation keys to the settings window</li>
			<li>- added this window, it opens every patch and you can open it from the settings and the actions menu</li>
			<li>- patch notes will now only be displayed once per update</li>
			<li>- changed road building to be on by default (only applies to new saves)</li>
			<li>- changed how letters generated by random events are displayed for readability as suggested by zuki in our Discord server</li>
			<li>- changed how we handle version numbers</li>
			<li>- fixed pawns acquired from raiding don't have a valid guest tracker. Thanks to SodiumMeal for the report!</li>
			<li>- fixed floatmenu options for drop pods aiming at this mods settlements are not displayed correctly</li>
			<li>- fixed militar efficiency is not taken into account properly</li>
			<li>- fixed settlementsAutoBattle setting doesn't get saved on update</li>
		</patchNoteLines>

		<additionalNotes>
			<li>I want to give many thanks to our testers TheBoredGal and smaboo!</li>
		</additionalNotes>

		<patchNoteImagePaths>
			<li>PatchNoteImages/0.39.00/0</li>
			<li>PatchNoteImages/0.39.00/1</li>
			<li>PatchNoteImages/0.39.00/2</li>
		</patchNoteImagePaths>
		
		<patchNoteImageDescriptions>
			<li>The new Patch note window. The optimal size for new images is 1366x768. As you can see there are still artifacts making it not look perfect and I don't know why (send help).\nThis entire window took me ~a week of coding, not sure if that's fast or slow, but the ability to show messages like this was really important to me.\nAlso we can maybe reuse this code to make an ingame Wiki for Empire :P\nI'll probably use this in the future to give details on new features that I wouldn't normally put out there, and added some to older patches here too</li>
			<li>A patch note def file. It describes the information contained in a patch note and can easily be used by other mods as well. Though atm Empire would have to be active. The screenshot here is not from the final version.</li>
			<li>Pressing the "Force Open" option seen here will lock the window open, allowing you to make multiple changes without having to open it multiple times.</li>
		</patchNoteImageDescriptions>
		
		<authors>
			<li>Danimineiro</li>
			<li>Imperitor</li>
		</authors>
	</FactionColonies.PatchNoteDef>

	<FactionColonies.PatchNoteDef ParentName="EmpirePatchBase">
		<defName>0_38_01</defName>
		<label>HotFix</label>
		<description>Small HotFix</description>

		<major>0</major>
		<minor>38</minor>
		<patch>1</patch>

		<releaseDay>1</releaseDay>
		<releaseMonth>12</releaseMonth>
		<releaseYear>2021</releaseYear>

		<patchNoteType>Hotfix</patchNoteType>

		<patchNoteLines>
			<li>- fixed some settlement names causing the new short name feature to break</li>
		</patchNoteLines>

		<authors>
			<li>Danimineiro</li>
		</authors>
	</FactionColonies.PatchNoteDef>
	
	<FactionColonies.PatchNoteDef ParentName="EmpirePatchBase">
		<defName>0_38_00</defName>
		<label>HotFix</label>
		<description>Small HotFix</description>

		<major>0</major>
		<minor>38</minor>
		<patch>0</patch>

		<releaseDay>26</releaseDay>
		<releaseMonth>11</releaseMonth>
		<releaseYear>2021</releaseYear>

		<patchNoteType>Hotfix</patchNoteType>

		<patchNoteLines>
			<li>- fixed scrolling issue in settlement window</li>
			<li>- fixed faction icon never updates (you have to restart your game after changing it to apply changes)</li>
		</patchNoteLines>

		<authors>
			<li>Danimineiro</li>
		</authors>
	</FactionColonies.PatchNoteDef>

	<FactionColonies.PatchNoteDef ParentName="EmpirePatchBase">
		<defName>0_37_09</defName>
		<label>Military deployment rework update</label>
		<description>A minor update fixing a lot of bugs</description>

		<major>0</major>
		<minor>37</minor>
		<patch>9</patch>

		<releaseDay>26</releaseDay>
		<releaseMonth>11</releaseMonth>
		<releaseYear>2021</releaseYear>

		<patchNoteType>Minor</patchNoteType>

		<patchNoteLines>
			<li>- changed how settlements work as a step towards SoS/RimWar compatibility - all thanks to Imperitor</li>
			<li>- added new sharper building icons made by turkler</li>
			<li>- reworked military deployment:</li>
			<li>	- pawns can no longer be drafted (this feature is too buggy, could be exploited, and can cause compatibility issues with other mods)</li>
			<li>	- All bugs related to this system should be fixed now</li>
			<li>	- fixed mercenaries getting deep saved when they shouldn't be</li>
			<li>	- fixed payment is taken for military extra squads before they actually deploy</li>
			<li></li>
			<li>- reworked tax delivery caravan behaviour</li>
			<li>	- fixed delivery pawns don't drop items when engaged on low story danger</li>
			<li>	- fixed delivery pawns dig through terrain when trying to leave and normal routes are blocked by enemies</li>
			<li>	- fixed the caravan tax delivery lord crashes if the last pawn goes missing unexpectedly</li>
			<li>	- maybe fixed delivery Caravan pawns can get stuck in player home zone</li>
			<li>	- delivery pawns no longer charge enemies, instead they now defend your tax spot and only fight enemies approaching it</li>
			<li></li>
			<li>- added the ability to modify worker count using shift + ctrl</li>
			<li>- added a new short name field during settlement customization</li>
			<li>- added your name to the patch notes for steam users</li>
			<li>- added the ability to translate more strings (major rework here soon)</li>
			<li>- added a need for mochi to a dev, but it is too expensive for him :(</li>
			<li>- added missing upkeep cost to shuttle port building string</li>
			<li>- fixed most cases in which settlement names can be too long</li>
			<li>- fixed quest related prisoners can be send to settlements</li>
			<li>- fixed camera leaves world map after sending an existing caravan on the world map using the shuttle buildings abilities</li>
			<li>- fixed min/max days setting for military encounters isn't getting saved</li>
			<li>- fixed imprisoning owned slaves that originate from your faction causes unrest</li>
			<li>- fixed newly rolled pawns can have biocoded (0 cost) weapons</li>
			<li>- fixed "Attack {0}" when selecting enemy settlements</li>
			<li>- removed unrest gain from faction pawns dying, if player wasn't involved</li>
			<li>- removed some message spam</li>
		</patchNoteLines>

		<additionalNotes>
			<li>I want to give many thanks to our testers TheBoredGal and smaboo!</li>
			<li>Also thanks for Turkler for the art and the community for providing bug reports!</li>
		</additionalNotes>

		<patchNoteImagePaths>
			<li>PatchNoteImages/0.37.09/0</li>
		</patchNoteImagePaths>

		<patchNoteImageDescriptions>
			<li>Some of Turklers new Icons</li>
		</patchNoteImageDescriptions>

		<authors>
			<li>Danimineiro</li>
			<li>Imperitor</li>
		</authors>
	</FactionColonies.PatchNoteDef>

	<FactionColonies.PatchNoteDef ParentName="EmpirePatchBase">
		<defName>0_37_06</defName>
		<label>BugFix update</label>
		<description>A minor update fixing a lot of bugs</description>

		<major>0</major>
		<minor>37</minor>
		<patch>6</patch>

		<releaseDay>08</releaseDay>
		<releaseMonth>11</releaseMonth>
		<releaseYear>2021</releaseYear>

		<patchNoteType>Minor</patchNoteType>

		<patchNoteLines>
			<li>- changed a few floatmenus to be searchable</li>
			<li>- changed how remaining time is displayed when the remaining time is less than a day</li>
			<li>- fixed a NullException for Linux users</li>
			<li>- fixed new units can have biocoded weapons with 0 cost</li>
			<li>- fixed military or worker pawns can generate without being able to be violent</li>
			<li>- fixed all beds become prisoner beds when sending a prisoner to a settlement</li>
			<li>- fixed selecting a race during unit creation doesn't work</li>
			<li>- fixed random event goods not being send</li>
			<li>- fixed mercenary not joining the player when they should</li>
			<li>- fixed some race combinations don't generate PawnGenOptions for all races selected</li>
			<li>- fixed a bug where some races couldn't be removed from the Race Filter</li>
			<li>- fixed Race filter error showing on new saves unnecessarily</li>
			<li>- added translatability to some strings</li>
		</patchNoteLines>

		<additionalNotes>
			<li>I want to give many thanks to our testers TheBoredGal and smaboo!</li>
		</additionalNotes>

		<patchNoteImagePaths>
			<li>PatchNoteImages/0.37.06/0</li>
			<li>PatchNoteImages/0.37.06/1</li>
		</patchNoteImagePaths>

		<patchNoteImageDescriptions>
			<li>A searchable floatmenu</li>
			<li>The new event timer</li>
		</patchNoteImageDescriptions>

		<authors>
			<li>Danimineiro</li>
			<li>Big_Bad_E</li>
		</authors>
	</FactionColonies.PatchNoteDef>
	
	<FactionColonies.PatchNoteDef ParentName="EmpirePatchBase">
		<defName>0_37_03</defName>
		<label>BugFix update</label>
		<description>A minor update fixing a lot of bugs</description>

		<major>0</major>
		<minor>37</minor>
		<patch>3</patch>

		<releaseDay>03</releaseDay>
		<releaseMonth>11</releaseMonth>
		<releaseYear>2021</releaseYear>

		<patchNoteType>Minor</patchNoteType>

		<patchNoteLines>
			<li>- added new building: Shuttle Port (Techlevel: Spacer). The art for this building was made by turkler and some text written by Shalax!</li>
			<li>- shuttles are now only send by settlements with a shuttle port building</li>
			<li>- added a new setting to force specific delivery modes, including the old legacy spawning on the tax spot</li>
			<li>- added a new button to settlements on the world map that allows you to open the settlements window from there</li>
			<li>- made shuttles wait for landing spots to be cleared before landing</li>
			<li>- delivery caravans now wait if the map is dangerous to enter</li>
			<li>- reworked the delivery setting: you can now force any type of delivery for any delivery</li>
			<li>- fixed racefilter resulting in pawnKindDef lists that have no traders (fixed being unable to trade with settlements as caravan)</li>
			<li>- fixed shuttle landing cells (should work like vanilla shuttles now)</li>
			<li>- fixed no animals selectable for animal tithe</li>
			<li>- fixed time till tax is negative before faction is formed</li>
			<li>- fixed random event names not displaying properly</li>
			<li>- fixed double settlement defence when automatic resolve is enabled</li>
			<li>- fixed delivering pawns get stuck if the tax spot can't be reached</li>
			<li>- fixed daysBetweenTaxes can be set to 0</li>
			<li>- fixed visually high tax base number</li>
			<li>- fixed prisoners can be send to settlements on dangerous maps</li>
			<li>- fixed drop pods crashing through roofs (tax delivery)</li>
			<li>- maybe fixed empty tax deliveries</li>
			<li>- changed a RaceFilter error to be a warning instead</li>
			<li>- changed new military/worker pawns to spawn at a reasonable age ~21 to ~50 years of age (relative to race lifespan) (no more child soldiers, sorry)</li>
		</patchNoteLines>

		<additionalNotes>
			<li>I want to give many thanks to our testers TheBoredGal and smaboo!</li>
			<li>The shuttle port and functionality was suggested by turkler and refined by members of the discord and the modding team!</li>
		</additionalNotes>

		<patchNoteImagePaths>
			<li>PatchNoteImages/0.37.03/0</li>
			<li>PatchNoteImages/0.37.03/1</li>
		</patchNoteImagePaths>

		<patchNoteImageDescriptions>
			<li>The new shuttle port building</li>
			<li>The new settlement information button next to the shuttle port ability buttons.\nThe shuttle port allows you to summon a shuttle to any map with colonists or caravan that you own for transportating. Each port has three charges and a cooldown that resets each tax period.</li>
		</patchNoteImageDescriptions>

		<authors>
			<li>Danimineiro</li>
		</authors>
	</FactionColonies.PatchNoteDef>
	
	<FactionColonies.PatchNoteDef ParentName="EmpirePatchBase">
		<defName>0_37_00</defName>
		<label>BugFix update</label>
		<description>A minor update fixing a lot of bugs</description>

		<major>0</major>
		<minor>37</minor>
		<patch>0</patch>

		<releaseDay>29</releaseDay>
		<releaseMonth>10</releaseMonth>
		<releaseYear>2021</releaseYear>

		<patchNoteType>Minor</patchNoteType>

		<patchNoteLines>
			<li>- Implemented a new tax delivery system</li>
			<li>- Manual settlement defence is now disabled by default in preparation for a new system</li>
			<li>- Tax letters now combine items of the same type</li>
			<li>- The chance for random events can now be adjusted in the settings</li>
			<li>- fixed random pawns can be empire (royality) pawns</li>
			<li>- fixed race filter resets on load</li>
			<li>- fixed race filter resets when second race is enabled</li>
			<li>- fixed invincible animals</li>
			<li>- fixed values clipping in the overview window</li>
			<li>- fixed settlement defence battle not ending on colonist death/down</li>
			<li>- fixed downed pawns being removed from player faction during settlement defence if they came from the player</li>
			<li>- fixed caravan vanishing when engaging settlement defence</li>
			<li>- fixed original colonists being unable to leave a settlement defence map</li>
			<li>- fixed map generation error when the ideology of a pawn is missing</li>
		</patchNoteLines>

		<additionalNotes>
			<li>I want to give many thanks to our testers TheBoredGal and smaboo!</li>
		</additionalNotes>

		<patchNoteImagePaths>
			<li>PatchNoteImages/0.37.00/0</li>
			<li>PatchNoteImages/0.37.00/1</li>
		</patchNoteImagePaths>

		<patchNoteImageDescriptions>
			<li>A tax caravan</li>
			<li>The new random event settings slider</li>
		</patchNoteImageDescriptions>

		<authors>
			<li>Danimineiro</li>
		</authors>
	</FactionColonies.PatchNoteDef>

	<FactionColonies.PatchNoteDef ParentName="EmpirePatchBase">
		<defName>0_36_09</defName>
		<label>HotFix</label>
		<description>A minor update fixing a lot of bugs</description>

		<major>0</major>
		<minor>36</minor>
		<patch>9</patch>

		<releaseDay>17</releaseDay>
		<releaseMonth>10</releaseMonth>
		<releaseYear>2021</releaseYear>

		<patchNoteType>Hotfix</patchNoteType>

		<patchNoteLines>
			<li>- fixed trait spam bug</li>
			<li>- fixed several bugs during settlement defence</li>
			<li>- fixed attempting to scarify animals</li>
			<li>- fixed pawns getting discarded after joining an ongoing settlement defence event using drop pods</li>
			<li>- fixed a bug concerning trading that sometimes occurs after a caravan appeared on a settlement after settlement defence</li>
		</patchNoteLines>

		<additionalNotes>
			<li>I want to give many thanks to our testers TheBoredGal and smaboo!</li>
		</additionalNotes>

		<patchNoteImagePaths>
			<li>PatchNoteImages/0.36.09/0</li>
		</patchNoteImagePaths>

		<patchNoteImageDescriptions>
			<li>The trait spam bug</li>
		</patchNoteImageDescriptions>

		<authors>
			<li>Danimineiro</li>
		</authors>
	</FactionColonies.PatchNoteDef>

	<FactionColonies.PatchNoteDef ParentName="EmpirePatchBase">
		<defName>0_36_00</defName>
		<label>The 1.3 Release</label>
		<description>The 1.3 Release</description>

		<major>0</major>
		<minor>36</minor>
		<patch>0</patch>

		<releaseDay>15</releaseDay>
		<releaseMonth>10</releaseMonth>
		<releaseYear>2021</releaseYear>

		<patchNoteType>Major</patchNoteType>

		<patchNoteLines>
			<li>- 1.3 is released on Steam workshop</li>
		</patchNoteLines>

		<additionalNotes>
			<li>I want to give many thanks to our testers TheBoredGal and smaboo!</li>
			<li>If someone digs up the patch notes for that I'll put them here</li>
		</additionalNotes>

		<authors>
			<li>Danimineiro</li>
		</authors>
	</FactionColonies.PatchNoteDef>
</Defs>