<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<LanguageData>

<AlreadyUpgradeSettlement>This settlement is already being upgraded!</AlreadyUpgradeSettlement>
<StartUpgradeSettlement>The settlement is now being upgraded...</StartUpgradeSettlement>

<BuildingInvalidEnvironment>That building cannot be built on this settlement's biome!</BuildingInvalidEnvironment>

<FCDescSeaIce>Endless sheets of ice unbroken by nothing, little animals, and no food except that which is grown in heated rooms. Only the most tenacious of life survives here.</FCDescSeaIce>
<FCDescIceSheet>Bleak, unending frost blankets the land, interrupted only by outcroppings of stone and ruins. The only source of food is the hardy wildlife which calls this place its home.</FCDescIceSheet>
<FCDescTundra>The hinterland houses a variety of rugged flora and fauna eking out an existance on the moss-covered landscape. When the summer comes, the land blooms into life, if only briefly.</FCDescTundra>
<FCDescColdBog>The rugged beauty of this land is matched only by its inhospitability. Marshes dot the landscape, as do frequent packs of migrating herbivores and the predators that follow them.</FCDescColdBog>
<FCDescBorealForest>While typically less cold than the hinterland of a tundra, a boreal forest's harsh weather is only matched by its warm summers, where green blooms and food becomes plentiful until next winter.</FCDescBorealForest>
<FCDescTropicalRainforest>Trees choke the sky, ensuring little light reaches the floor. Regardless, there is a dazzling, but deadly, array of flora and fauna. The beauty of this biome is matched only by the dangers within.</FCDescTropicalRainforest>
<FCDescTemperateForest>Abundant forests and streams split the land. Animals roam the thick forests and both food and shelter are aplenty.</FCDescTemperateForest>
<FCDescTemperateSwamp>The land is covered by bogs and marshes, and what isn't, is covered by a variety of vegetation. Available building space is at a premium here.</FCDescTemperateSwamp>
<FCDescTropicalSwamp>Both the sky and ground is strangled by vegetation, as trees reach for the sky, ensuring little light reaches the treacherous grounds. Disease is rampant and frequent.</FCDescTropicalSwamp>
<FCDescAridShrubland>While not a true desert, growing soil is at a premium thanks to the relentless heat. Most of the land is open, with secluded groves breaking the otherwise empty skyline.</FCDescAridShrubland>
<FCDescDesert>Arable soil is a rarity, as the majority of the land here is covered in sand, some too treacherous to build on.  Still, life clings to existance here, and the sands harbour a vibrant array of life</FCDescDesert>
<FCDescExtremeDesert>The sun has baked this land into a wasteland. There is almost no soil that can support proper vegetation, and that which there is, is poor in quality. </FCDescExtremeDesert>
<FCDescUnknown>Little is widely known about the surrounding land, but the colony manages to survive and prosper in their present conditions.</FCDescUnknown>



<FCTownLevel1>The settlement itself is simply a small cluster of buildings grouped around a central structure.</FCTownLevel1>
<FCTownLevel2>The settlement is dominated by a few large structures, but it is still quite small. A number of sandbags and barricades ring the outside.</FCTownLevel2>
<FCTownLevel3>The settlement has a good number of structures, largely production oriented, as well as dedicated storehouses, and busy workers scurry between them. A modest wall protects the settlement.</FCTownLevel3>
<FCTownLevel4>The settlement is reasonably large, and well organised, with a number of industrial buildings clustered together to maximize efficiency. A thick wall and internal defenses protect the colony from attack.</FCTownLevel4>
<FCTownLevel5>Clearly labelled buildings mark the industrial heart of this bustling beacon of civilization, as well as various other utilities . Multiple walls ring the colony, with plentiful interior defenses in carefully planned chokepoints.</FCTownLevel5>

</LanguageData>